# Alan Hardman

Web Developer — alan@phpizza.com

I've been coding since I was nine, and plan to keep doing it forever. I've primarily focused on PHP web development, but have experience in many other languages and platforms as well. I'm the type of person that uses about five different operating systems a day, codes in several different languages, and constantly tweaks personal servers and network infrastructure.

## Skills

- Backend web development
- Linux server administration
- Responsive web design
- UI/UX design
- Computer networking
- Performance optimization
- Web application security

## Proficient technologies

- Languages: PHP 5/7, JavaScript (ES6/Node), HTML5, CSS/LESS/SCSS, Python, C#
- Servers: nginx, Apache, MySQL, Docker
- Operating Systems: Linux, Windows, macOS, Chrome OS

## Experience

CTO/Co-Founder - StructHub, Inc., December 2018 - Present

- Designed and developed a website and web application for customers
- Architected a server cluster for running the production website and APIs, including static file distribution via a CDN
- Designed and developed a mobile application for consumers, using React Native

#### Senior Web Developer - Thrive Life, March 2013 - December 2018

- Developed custom modules for Magento eCommerce platform in PHP
- Set up and maintained Linux web server cluster with nginx and MySQL
  - Later updated PHP 5.2-based codebase to run on PHP 7.2
- Re-architected codebase and server environment for PCI DSS D compliance
- Built API and web app for managing third-party orders
  - Included integrations with Amazon MWS and Shopify to process orders automatically
- Developed open-source project management system phproject.org
  - Currently in use by entire company to track projects, tasks, bugs, and kaizens.
- 2014 Employee of the Year

#### **Lead Developer** – Cubik Network, 2012 – 2013

- Developed a flexible PHP-based social network platform
- Designed a responsive app interface for the web site
- Set up and maintained Apache-based Linux web servers

#### **Designer** – Driscoll for Senate, 2012

- Designed branding for campaign including logo and colors
- Built and maintained responsive website

## **Awards**

- BSA Eagle Scout
- Business Professionals of America National Top 10, 2012
  - Web Application Development
  - Visual Basic .NET Programming

#### Education

Billings Senior High School - Billings, MT - 2009-2012

## Conference talks

- "The Road to Open Source" OpenWest 2015
  - Ryan Bouché and I discuss the ways we used the Open Source model at Thrive Life to build the Phproject project management system.

#### Links

- GitHub https://github.com/Alanaktion
- Linkedin https://www.linkedin.com/pub/alan-hardman/37/a36/17